Pamela Whisenhunt

Austin, TX | (336) 266-9588 | pam.s.whisenhunt@gmail.com | pswhisenhunt.com

Summary

I am a highly motivated, quick learner who is seeking a software engineering position. I have 3+ years experience as a full stack engineer and I specialize in front end engineering. I aim to find a position at a company with quality engineering and ample growth opportunities.

Skills

Frontend: JavaScript (TypeScript, React, Redux, Backbone.js, Angular JS), HTML, CSS (Responsive Design and SASS), Tooling (npm, yarn, Webpack, Grunt.js), Testing (Mocha, Jasmine)

Backend: Node.js, PHP/Laravel, Groovy on Grails, MongoDB, MySQL, Redis; *familiar with Java*, Python, Ruby on Rails

Miscellaneous: Git/Github, *nix, Agile Methodologies and Software (Trello, Asana, Jira), Design thinking, UX/UI basics, Adobe XD, Adobe Illustrator and Photoshop basics.

Experiences

Full Stack Engineer, Front End Focused - Impactflow - Portland, OR - 10/2016 - 10/2017

At Impactflow, I was a member of a small team of engineers building an event management solutions tool.

- I independently developed the front end of several features using Backbone.js and contributed to our RESTful APIs using Laravel(PHP).
- Outside of engineering, I created the "Culture Club," which focused on building relationships between colleagues and departments by hosting biweekly social gatherings.

Full Stack Engineer - Red Ventures - Charlotte, NC - 10/2015 - 08/2016

At Red Ventures, I worked on a team that built proprietary tools for online chat.

- I contributed to a full rewrite of Articulate Chat, the primary chat application used by customer representatives to communicate with customers, using React, Redux, Node.js, and MongoDB.
- I led a full rewrite of the front end of Articulate Admin, a tool used to manage chat settings and chat operators, using React and Redux. While rewriting the application, I also redesigned the UI.
- I wrote Chat Reaper, a small Node is application that purged stale customer conversations in Redis.

Full Stack Engineer - New Iron, Inc. - Austin, TX - 1/2014 - 11/2014

At New Iron, I built an internal tool to help IT recruiters track and manage their candidates.

- I contributed to our backend API using Groovy on Grails.
- I refactored the front end from JQuery to AngularJS to improve maintainability, testing, and overall code quality. While refactoring, I redesigned the UI.
- I led biweekly product demos to showcase new and improved features to stakeholders and users.

Education

- Galvanize Full Stack Engineering Bootcamp Boulder, CO 2015
- Austin Community College Computer Science Courses Austin, TX 2013
- Bachelor of Science in Community Health Education UNC Wilmington Wilmington, NC 2011